准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
末日之外卖
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我饿死了
I am so hungry
完全没办法给自己做事情
and incapable of doing anything for myself
那你就走运了  我这位邋遢朋友
You're in luck, my slovenly friend
你可以一边邋里邋遢地瘫在那儿
While you sit there wallowing in your filth
一边让蟹堡王现做美食给你外卖过去
you can let the Krusty Krab
make and deliver your meal for ya
要是外卖十分钟内没到你手上
If your food isn't in your hands in ten minutes or less
就免免免
it's f-f-f
台词是  免费
The line is, "Free"
对  就他说的那样
Yeah, what he said
谢了  蟹堡王
Thank you, Krusty Krab
不用谢
You're welcome
我钱呢
Where's me money?
蟹堡王
呼叫KK-01KP
他们并不知道  蟹堡王的广告
Little did they know their Krusty commercial
竟会进入卑鄙无耻的
would reach the ignoble eyes of
邪恶帮眼中
the League of E.V.I.L.
我就爱油滋滋的蟹黄堡
I love those greasy Krabby Patties
对  但我讨厌拿钱去买东西
Yeah, but I hate paying for things
要是午后小零食到不了我手上
Well, if I don't get my afternoon snackies
那我就狠狠发脾气
I'm gonna throw a tantrum
说得对
You're right
所以就要搞个超级邪恶的阴谋
This calls for a deliciously diabolical scheme
来给蟹堡王下单
We place our order with the Krusty Krab
再使出我们的邪恶力量
then use our powers of evil
害外卖小哥超时
to ensure the delivery boy is late
这样就有免费午餐吃了
Then we get a free lunch
跟我笑吧  坏蛋们
Laugh with me, villains
笑吧
Laugh
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
喂
Hello?
我要五份蟹堡套餐  多加蟹堡酱
I'd like five Krabby Combos, extra Krusty sauce
改成四份  加一份儿童堡
Make that four and a Pipsqueak Patty kid's meal
送给
Make it out to
射线恶魔
Man Ray
地址就在邪恶帮秘密基地
Deliver to League of E.V.I.L. secret hideout
加油站后面的不祥巷
Ominous Alley, behind the gas station
感谢
Thank you
不用  谢
No, thank--
坏蛋们
Villains
各就各位
Battle stations
蟹堡王
同时
Meanwhile
别忘了  海绵宝宝
Now remember, SpongeBob
这次的外卖一定得快
this delivery's gotta be quick
而且得直接放到客人手上
and you gotta put it directly in the customer's hand
我可不想白送霸王餐
I ain't givin' out no free meals
遵命  老板
Aye-aye, sir
可是
But
你说我能不能顺便找坏蛋
Do you think I'll have time for the villains
给我漫画签名吧
to sign my comic book?
正联
赶紧进炮里就是了
Just get in the cannon
拉
Pull
砸
邪恶帮基地
在这
秘密入口
"Secret entrance"
一听就有反派本色
Sounds villainous
肯定就是这里了
This must be the place
等一下
Wait a second
海绵宝宝急中生智
Thinking quickly
拿出了水动力锅铲
SpongeBob reached for his hydrodynamic spatula
还带着左右铲配件
with port and starboard attachments
还剩八分钟
Eight minutes to spare
多半会跟公园散步一样轻松
This'll be a walk in the park
我是说  洞穴散步
I mean, cave
想干嘛  小不点
Whattaya want, bub?
蟹堡王外卖
Krusty delivery
我认得你
I know you
你是
You're
重罪犯海伦
Helen the Felon
爱惹麻烦的熊孩子
The trouble-making tyke
没错
That's right
我要关你禁闭  害你超时
And I'm giving you a time-out
可  可我要送外卖啊
B-But I'm making a delivery
蟹老板说我得送到你手上
And Mr. Krabs says I have to put it right in your hand
不是我手上
Not my hand
是射线恶魔手上
Man Ray's hand
想找到他  就得先打开这扇门
You're gonna have to open this door
if you wanna get to him
好
Okay
放弃外卖袋吧  小弟弟
Give up the bag, buddy boy
你绝对不可能准时到射线恶魔那边
You'll never make it to Man Ray on time
不可能
Never
没力气  转不动把手
Too weak to turn knob
那就使出我的翻肉饼手
I'll use my patty flipping hand
不公平
No fair
你那是作弊
That's cheatin'
脑震荡
真对不起
Sorry about that
话说我能找你要签名吗
Say, can I get your autograph?
当然能
Of course
多谢了
Gee, thanks
还剩六分钟
Six minutes to spare
蟹堡王外卖
Krusty delivery
真不敢相信
I can't believe it
那是
That's
巨霸虾
Jumbo Shrimp
行为最恶劣的头号人物
The biggest name in bad behavior
你这是想去哪儿  小薯条
And just where do you think you're going, small fry?
蟹  蟹堡王外卖
K-Krusty delivery
送给射线恶魔
for Man Ray?
想找他  就得先过我这关
If you wanna get to him, you'll have to go through me
不要
No
拜托
Please
小不点
你漫画形象看着大多了
You look bigger in the comics
可不可以给我签下名啊
Do you think you could sign this for me?
好啊
Gladly
那
So, uh
你是粉丝吗
you're a fan?
是铁粉呢
Huge
别走
Wait
我跟你还没完呢  小东西
I'm not done with you, little guy
给我回来
Get back here
就剩四分钟了
Four minutes
得快点了
Better hurry
出口
这是什么地方
Where am I?
闪亮又干净
我
I
一定是拐错弯了
must have taken a wrong turn
未来的清洁剂
查理泡泡
顽固污渍我来搞定
×
还真是  你这笨海绵
You certainly did, you simpleminded sponge
准备好深深陷入
Prepare to be ensnared by the--
肮脏泡泡
The Dirty Bubble
能找你签名吗
Can I get your autograph?
不要
No
别  等一下
N-no, wait
又来了
Not again
爆
肮脏泡泡
Dirty Bubble
射线恶魔在哪呢
Now where's Man Ray?
蟹堡王外卖
K-Krusty d-delivery
早该料到的
I should have known
是
It's, uh
海底番茄潜艇
Sub-Marinara
邪恶的肉丸潜艇堡
The maniacal meatball sub
没关系
No matter
我可不会被食物给打败
I could never be defeated by food
我可是个
I am a
煎炸厨师
fry cook
俏皮
两面包夹
不会吧
Oh, no
我被食物打败了
I've been defeated by food
不好了
Oh, no
这只邪恶的三明治正准备着
This sinister spuccadella is preparing
要把我们的英雄泡进他举世闻名的
to marinate our hero in his famous
灼热意式香辣番茄酱里
extra spicy molten arrabbiata sauce
海绵宝宝会如何摆脱这三明治的魔爪
How will SpongeBob escape this harrowing hoagie?
放心  旁白先生
Don't worry, Mr. Narrator
我知道怎么办
I know what to do
那就办啊
Well, then do it
看来我面包吃饱了
Looks like I filled up on bread
填 满
该打包剩菜了
Now to wrap up the leftovers
能给我签名吗
Will you sign this for me?
谢了
Thanks
看来你又被挫败了
Looks like you've been foiled again
锡箔纸
超新鲜
既然还在等外卖
While I wait for my delivery
那就趁机打发点时间吧
I might as well kill some time
巨鼻侠
The Tremendous Trunk
鼻子能通晓一切的象海豹
The elephant seal whose nose knows all
放我走  射线恶魔
Let me go, Man Ray
我已经闻出你的邪恶事迹了
I've already sniffed out your evil deeds
你唯一会闻到的东西
The only thing you'll be sniffing
就是这块臭奶酪
is this stinky cheese
不要
No
别放林堡奶酪啊
Not Limburger
我还有孩子啊
I have children
蟹堡王外卖
Krusty delivery
而且还剩十秒钟
And with ten seconds to spare
我的午餐外卖
My lunch order
快来放我手上吧
Well, go ahead and put it in my hand
好
Yes
外卖已送达
Delivery complete
确实  可是呢
Yes, but it was
超时一秒钟了
one second late
超时
所以说
That means
我们的外卖
our meal
免费了
is free
嘲笑他吧  坏蛋们
Laugh at him, villains
笑吧
Laugh
小子
Hey, kid
能不能帮个忙
A little help here?
嗨  巨鼻侠
Hi, Tremendous Trunk
我会救你的
Sure, I'll free you
能找你要签名吗
Can I have your autograph?
这就签
Here you go
不过你听我说
But listen, pal
既然你帮了我  那我也会帮你
you helped me, so I'll help you
巨鼻侠使出他巨鼻的超能力
With the prodigious power of his potent proboscis
一个喷嚏就带海绵宝宝穿越回了过去
The Tremendous Trunk sneezed SpongeBob
back through time itself
一分钟零七秒前
蟹堡王外卖
Krusty delivery
已送达
delivered
总共12块
That'll be $12
那个嘛
Well, you see
邪恶帮其实破产了
The League of E.V.I.L. is actually broke
结果犯罪就是得不偿失
Turns out crime doesn't pay
没事
Well, that's okay
我来付
I'll cover it
谢谢你们送的小费
Thanks for the tip
在这签名吧
Sign here, please
谢谢你们  坏蛋们
Thank you, evil villains
不对
No
谢谢你  海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
多保重
Gesundheit
[ 专用于礼貌回复打喷嚏者的套话 ]
谢了
Thanks
本集完
我的老爸
是条船
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
客串
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
离我钱远一点
Get away from me money
老爸
Daddy
我终于想好可以让你买什么
I finally figured out what you can get me
当我下周的生日礼物了
for my birthday next week
我找到了最适合你买给我的船
I found the perfect boat for you to buy me
船
Boat?
我又没说要给你买船当生日礼物啊
I never said I'd buy you a birthday boat
珍珍
Pearl
只要你把那震耳欲聋的音乐关了
If you stop playing that earsplitting music
我就给你买条新船当你生日礼物
I'll buy you a new boat for your birthday
你没在偷偷录音吧
You're not recording me, are ya?
只有这条船适合我  价格只要一万块
It's the only boat for me and it's only 10,000 clams
一
T-t-t-t-ten
万块
Th-th-th-thousand?
新船要到手
Gonna get a new boat
我不害人愁
I'm not bratty
生日礼物船
A birthday boat
要老爸送给我
From my daddy
我可真多嘴啊
Me and my big mouth
就在那了  海绵宝宝
There it is, SpongeBob
我女儿的生日礼物船
me daughter's birthday boat
我好喜欢
I love it
不是小册子
Not the brochure
这破烂老爷船不错嘛
Nice fixer-upper
可是干嘛不直接买条新船呢
but why didn't you just buy a new boat?
因为我才不花一万冤枉钱买新船
Because I'm not paying 10,000 clams for a new boat
你得来给我修理这条船
You're gonna help me fix up this boat
要修得跟小册子上的船一样好
so it's as good as the brochure boat
我家珍珍肯定看不出区别
Me Pearl will never know the difference
可能得要一阵子
This may take a while
过了一个一阵子后
好耶
Zow-ie
这船一看就像是值一百万的样子
This boat looks like it costs a million clams
至少外观确实像
Well, at least on the outside
趁珍珍没醒  找来发动机就行
Now we just gotta find an engine before Pearl wakes up
到我生日了
My birthday
快躲起来
We gotta hide
珍珍要来了  小子
Pearl's a-coming, boy-o
新船要到手
Gonna get a new boat
我不害人愁
I'm not bratty
生日礼物船
A birthday boat
要老爸送给我
From my daddy
快来一条
B-O-A-T
船
Boat?
珍珍
还真是我要的船
It's the boat that I wanted
我爱我老爸
I love my daddy
我要来试驾一下
I'll take a test drive
就是这样
That's the stuff
没等老爸醒来  我就会回来
I'll be back before Daddy wakes up
她没发动机开不了船
She can't drive a boat with no engine
珍珍
Hey, Pearl
别吵
Quiet
不能让她发现这船是垃圾
She can't find out this is a piece of junk
那要怎么办
Well, how will we do that?
假装呗
Fake it
咱俩当发动机
We'll be the engine
来火力全开  看看这船有什么本事
Let's open her up and see what this baby can do
小子宝宝  我的海绵
Boy-Bob, me sponge
你负责转船轴
You're on axle duty
遵命  船长
Aye-Aye, Cap'n
有导航系统
A navigation system
去裤头村高中最快的路是哪条
What's the quickest route to Bikini Bottom High School?
我要去接我朋友
I want to pick up my friends
朋友
Friends?
油腻青少年休想上这条船
I don't want any greasy teenagers in this boat
什么
What?
我是说
I mean
前方路口左转
Turn left at the intersection
高中
你船好酷啊  珍珍
Cool boat, Pearl
别闲聊了  姐妹们
Quit gawking, girls
上船吧
and hop in
珍珍
Pearl
来放点音乐吧
Let's have some music
什么
What?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
开嗓
Start singing
我的耳朵
My ears
赶紧关了
Shut it off
希望她们没把我壳给摔裂了
I hope they didn't crack my shell open
刹车  小子
Hit the brakes, boy-o
你船不错嘛  珍珍
Nice wheels, Pearl
没想到你爸这样的铁老公鸡
I never thought an old skinflint like your dad
会给你买条船啊
would buy you a boat
这小流氓说谁老啊
Who's this hoodlum calling old?
滚远点  鲨老大
Take a hike, Sharkface
除非鲨鱼想比一把
Unless you want a shark race?
啦啦队想比一把是吧
A cheerleader race, huh?
拿好你们的啦啦球
Hold on to your pom-poms
比比  比赛吗
R-r-r-race?
不好了
Oh no
比赛吗
A race?
可好了
Oh yes
一边凉快去  海绵宝宝
Take a break, SpongeBob
我来搞定这个飞机头混账
This pompadoured punk is mine
停
蟹老板  不觉得我们该开慢一点吗
Mr. Krabs, don't you think we should slow down a little?
还不能慢下来
We can't slow down now
这兔崽子已经被我捏得死死的了
I got this snot-nose right where I want him
珍珍
Pearl
用 牙
全力应对那些玩意
Sink your teeth into those
[ defeat（挫败）与 feet（脚）谐音 ]
挫败感真难受
The agony of defeat
想到了  小子
That's it, boy-o
你腿全给我
I need all your legs
再生越快越好
As fast as you can grow 'em
好像有办法了
I smell a plan
加把劲  小船
Go get 'em, boat
进攻
Sic 'em
啦啦队就该老实待在运动场的草皮上
Cheerleaders should stay on their astro-turf
别来上路
and off the road
你们这些玩意好像不小心掉了
You seem to have dropped these
妈啊
Mommy
我的心跳得比那几条鲨鱼还快
My heart is racing faster than those sharks
我还要更多刺激
I want more excitement
更多惊险
More thrills
还要狠狠狂开这条船
More vehicular mayhem
对  就比如说撞船大赛
Yeah, like a demolition derby
什么
What?
对  就比如说撞船大赛
Yeah, like a demolition derby
谁说的话
Who said that?
真是个好主意
That's a great idea
我的船天下无敌
My boat is invincible
撞船大赛
小子们好啊
Hello, boys
珍珍  珍珍
Pearl, Pearl
是我们的鲸鱼
She's our whale
体积庞大绝不出局
She is much too big to fail
加油  珍珍
Go, Pearl
看我的珍珍女生转身回身
Here's my Pearl Girl Twirl Hurl
再不逃出去  就会被珍珍害死的
If we don't get out of here, Pearl's gonna get us killed
要不要尝尝我的呼吸孔狂射
How about a Blowhole Blast
珍珍
Pearl
好个大猛攻
What a rush
在下正是撞船鲸神  宝贝
I'm a demolition whale, baby
不会吧
Oh, no
我把我新船怎么了
What did I do to my new boat?
老爸会宰了我的
Daddy's gonna kill me
这声音听着不太妙
That doesn't sound good
有点像我爸上厕所的声音
Sounds like my dad in the bathroom
在我听来呢
Yeah, sounds to me like
你发动机在缓慢痛苦地濒临一死
your engine is dying a slow, agonizing death
咱去把这船顶起来  修好它
Let's get it on the lift and fix 'er up
谢谢
Thank you
修船厂
汽船零件
小姐  我找到问题所在了
Well, young lady, I found the trouble
你船上就俩白痴
You got two knuckleheads
没有发动机
instead of an engine
老爸
Daddy?
你躲在我船里面干什么
What are you doing hiding inside of my boat?
我只是给你想造一条
I just wanted to build you
特别的礼物船  庆祝你生日
a special boat for your birthday
跟她解释  海绵宝宝
Tell her, SpongeBob
啊对
Ooh, yeah
我想起来了
I remember
蟹老板说
Mr. Krabs said
我才不花一万冤枉钱买新船
I'm not payin' 10,000 clams for a new boat
珍珍肯定看不出区别
Pearl will never know the difference
没你事了
Never mind
听我说  珍珍
Listen to me, Pearl
咱这应该只是
I think what we have here
互相体谅没到位吧
is simply a failure to commiserate
我听够你的话了  老爸
I've heard enough from you, Daddy
你还是老样子  想贪便宜
You tried to cheap out like always
还送我垃圾当生日礼物
and gift me a piece of junk for my birthday
你那种说法就有点难听了
Well, when you say it like that it sounds bad, yeah
我明白真正的问题所在了
I see the real trouble now
你口袋里不是有张信用卡吗
You got a credit card in your pocket
可以拿它来付款
that needs charging
所以我要用这卡来买一条新船
And I'm gonna charge a new boat on it
两条也行
Maybe two
我这边正好有两条新船待售
I just happen to have two new boats for sale right here
不过这俩船可贵了
But they're very expensive
等等  别啊
Wait, wait, wait, no
等等
Wait
两条船到手
I got two boats
我不害人愁
I'm not bratty
两条船到手  狠狠损我爸
I got two boats to spite my daddy